<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Kelly Ann Heilman, PhD</title>
    <link>https://Kah5.github.io/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://Kah5.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 17:35:45 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://Kah5.github.io/images/icon_huccf280dab276574ecd8f1c09072acb12_61809_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://Kah5.github.io/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>KVOA Tucson feature on our new paper in Global Change Biology!</title>
      <link>https://Kah5.github.io/post/kvoa-news-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 17:35:45 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Kah5.github.io/post/kvoa-news-article/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Margaret Evans and I had chance to catch up with Destiny Quinn, an achor for KVOA Tucson news to talk more about our recent paper in Global Change Biology! Check out the feature here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kvoa.com/news/uarizona-researchers-predict-a-decline-in-tree-growth/article_dd522930-89a9-11ec-af49-db5f4a9263e5.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Check out the feature and video here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/share/author/3PBGBXJMVPMY7C35ZPVY?target=10.1111/gcb.16038&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Global Change Biology paper is linked here.&lt;/a&gt; or contact me for a pdf.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Press coverage on our new paper in Global Change Biology!</title>
      <link>https://Kah5.github.io/post/in-the-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 17:35:45 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Kah5.github.io/post/in-the-news/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had the chance to catch up with journalist Mikayla Kelley to talk more about our recent paper in Global Change Biology! Check out the press release here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.arizona.edu/story/future-forests-will-have-smaller-trees-and-soak-less-carbon-study-suggests&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Check out the press release here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/share/author/3PBGBXJMVPMY7C35ZPVY?target=10.1111/gcb.16038&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Global Change Biology paper is linked here.&lt;/a&gt; or contact me for a pdf.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGU 2021 Poster Presentation</title>
      <link>https://Kah5.github.io/post/agu2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 17:35:45 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Kah5.github.io/post/agu2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed interacting with all of the AGU 2021 participants&amp;ndash;both in-person and virtual! I presented a poster on Tuesday on some of my work fusing tree ring and forest inventory data in a Bayesian state-space model framework to forecast tree diameter and diameter increment in ponderosa pine forests in Arizona (accepted in Global Change Biology, keep an eye out for it soon!), and the next steps we are taking to scale these forecasts to tree and plot-level aboveground biomass (+ uncertainty) in the Interior West US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you missed AGU, you can check out my poster here!&lt;/p&gt;





  
  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-agu-2021-poster&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://Kah5.github.io/post/agu2021/AGU_poster_2021_small_hudca36dbd37e81f331f0e1f5f0a72b0b0_1941632_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;AGU 2021 poster&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://Kah5.github.io/post/agu2021/AGU_poster_2021_small_hudca36dbd37e81f331f0e1f5f0a72b0b0_1941632_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;2666&#34; height=&#34;1500&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    AGU 2021 poster
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conferencing in the time of COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://Kah5.github.io/post/esa2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 17:35:45 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Kah5.github.io/post/esa2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just attended the annual meeting for Ecological Society of America (ESA), my first virtual conference! While I am disappointed that I couldn’t see everyone in person and visit Salt Lake City for the first time, virtual ESA 2020 had its benefits. It also had some downsides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-positives&#34;&gt;The Positives&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The virtual format allowed me to  interact with and digest the content of talks more easily. I could pause and look at figures &amp;amp; equations in detail, solving the age-old problem of presenters throwing a bunch of math onto a slide and expecting the audience to digest it in ~15 seconds (mea culpa). The ability to watch talks on my own time also meant that I could take the time I needed to jot down some notes, process, and reflect on the cool science I just heard about. I was also able to ask more questions and with more detail than in-person conferences. Also, if a talk wasn’t what I’d expected, I could get up and leave in the middle, which would be quite rude in-person&amp;ndash;I promise I didn’t do this very often!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-negatives&#34;&gt;The Negatives&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, virtual conferences come with some disadvantages. In particular, I had a lot of trouble accessing the synchronous live Q &amp;amp; A sessions, and I eventually gave up on this. I think that it will be hard to replace the interactions and networking that happens at in-person conferences, but hopefully we can come up with more creative solutions. I was disappointed that many people submitting only slides for the talks, which (to be honest) I haven’t taken the time to look though many of these yet. I understand that there may be some barriers to recording a talk&amp;ndash;listening to my voice on video is one of my least favorite things, and it took a few tries to record&amp;ndash;but the videos are more compelling, give way more information than just your slides, and you will reach a wider audience. Also, though the online format really lends itself to asking and answering questions, I was also disappointed at how few questions were asked on many of the talks I viewed. Perhaps some of these downsides can be improved upon, especially for conferences later this year which have more time switch to a virtual format, invest in hosting platforms, and develop new ways for us to interact in a COVID-19 world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;will-covid-19-change-conferences-for-the-better&#34;&gt;Will Covid-19 change conferences for the better?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortcomings aside, we should all give major thanks to the organizing committee, who turned ESA into a virtual conference on a short time-frame. Transitioning to all-virtual conferences is certainly a change for most of us, but I hope this experience will make future conferences more accessible to all, less fossil-fuel intensive (by reducing travel), and provide a diversity of ways to interact with other scientists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another upside of virtual conferences is that I now have a recorded research talk to share with the world. If you missed ESA, you can check out my talk here!




  
  





  





  


&lt;video controls &gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;https://Kah5.github.io/img/Heilman_ESA_2020_talk.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://Kah5.github.io/post/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 11:13:48 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Kah5.github.io/post/welcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my first blog, so here goes nothing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan to use this space to share posts covering a variety of topics ranging from reflections on recent research, teaching experiences, travel reflections, and some (hopefully) useful coding and teaching resources. Here is a bit more on what to expect:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;code--tutorials&#34;&gt;Code &amp;amp; tutorials:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my research, I have spent alot of time coding and learning new analyses, mostly in R/Rstudio. In this process, I have learned alot from forums, blogs, and other resources, and I plan to share some of this content (and hope it is useful).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;research&#34;&gt;Research:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to use this space to reflect on my recent research experiences, and highlight new publications. I may also do some reflections on past field work (with alot of pictures).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;travel&#34;&gt;Travel:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had the great privledge and opportunity to travel for both work and fun. The only time pick up my journal is during these trips, mostly so I can remember what I did, what I saw, on which trails I traveled, and where I camped. I plan to share some of these reflections here as well. Since travel has been put on hold for awhile (writing this in May 2020), I may dig up some of these old trips to share.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
